

# **Anton Zarubin**

Senior Node.js Developer / Team Leader

#### **Contact**

+38098 9309333

anton.zarubin@gmail.com

anton\_zarubin

github.com/zarant77

□□□ npmjs.com/~zarant77

## **Summary**

About ten years experience in PHP development.

Extensive experience in programming engineering and algorithm development.

Over three years experience in Node.js development.

Strong skills in development and implementation.

Abilities in inventing solutions, algorithms, methods and approaches.

Well skilled in database design and system architecture design.

Strong skill in "Single Page Application" development.

Good attention to details.

Native languages - Russian and Ukrainian. Conversational English.

#### Education

Graduated from Kharkiv National University of Radio Electronics in 2007, Masters Degree. Kharkiv, Ukraine.

M.S. in Computer Science, major in Computer Data Processing Systems.

# Skills

## **OS/Platform**

#	Windows 19 years (since 1998)	****
	Linux 13 years (since 2004)	****
	FreeBSD 2 years	★★★☆☆

# **Programming Language**

JS	JavaScript 13 years (since 2004)	****
<b>a</b>	HTML 13 years (since 2004)	****
巨	CSS 13 years (since 2004)	****
php	PHP 10 years	****
<b>G</b>	C++ 2 years	★★★☆☆
	Java 1 vear	★★☆☆☆

# **NoSQL DBMS**

•	MongoDB 1 year	***
	Couchbase 2 years	****
	Elasticsearch 2 years	****
	Redis 4 years (since 2013)	****

## **Relational DBMS**

	MS SQL 3 years	***
E. 5	MySQL 13 years (since 2004)	****
	PostgreSQL 1 year	

## ORM

	Sequelize 4 years (since 2013)	***
MONGÓÓSE'	Mongoose 1 year	***

# **Team Collaboration Tools**

<b>1</b>	Git 5 years	****
	Subversion 5 years	****
X	JIRA 2 years	★★★★☆
	Redmine 1 year	****
心	Target Process 1 year	★★★☆☆

# **Network Technologies**

REST	HTTP(S) REST 6 years (since 2011)	****
ON THE STATE OF TH	OAuth (1, 2) <i>1 year</i>	★★★☆☆
<u>B</u> 1	WebSockets 1 year	****

## Tools/Frameworks

(js)	Node.js 4 years (since 2013)	****
express	Express.js 4 years (since 2013)	****
hapi	HAPI Less than a year	****
<u>(</u>	jQuery 8 years (since 2009)	****
A	Angular 1 year	★★★☆☆
×	Backbone Less than a year	★★☆☆☆
	React Less than a year	****
	NW.js Less than a year	★★★☆☆
	PhoneGap Less than a year	
	Cordova Less than a year	
JADE	Jade 4 years (since 2013)	****
{less}	LESS 4 years (since 2013)	****
Sass	SASS Less than a year	
В	Bootstrap 4 years (since 2013)	****
Mi	Material-UI 13 years (since 2004)	****

## **Other Tools**

Gulp	Gulp 2 years (since 2015)	****
	Grunt 4 years (since 2013)	****
<u>जंग</u>	NPM 4 years (since 2013)	****
	Bower 4 years (since 2013)	****
API	ApiDoc 3 years (since 2014)	****
37MF	RAML 1 year	★★★☆☆
<b>(</b> <del>{··}</del> )	Swagger 1 year	★★★☆☆
mocha	Mocha 4 years (since 2013)	****
<b>JS</b> Hint	JSHint 3 years (since 2014)	****

#### **Experience**

#### 2014 - Present time, Node.js Developer

#### Freelancer (Odesk/Upwork) http://upwork.com/



More than year I used to work remotely for MarketWave. (http://www.market-wave.com/) MarketWave is company who provide customer multi-channels management (Phone, Live Chat, etc). Company provide sales support for visitors with key leaders of e-commerce. They was my general clients.

#### Primary Responsibilities:

Design, develop, test and deploy web applications

Develop appropriate code structures to solve specific tasks according to standards

Fix bugs, troubleshoot and resolve problems

Build flexible data models and seamless integration points

Comment code and write documentation using ApiDoc

Code review

#### Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: Node.js

Frameworks: Express, Angular, Bootstrap

Databases: MS SQL, Couchbase, Elasticsearch

Documentation: ApiDoc

QA: Mocha, JSHint

Another tools: Less, Jade, Grunt, Bower, NPM

#### 2012 - 2014, Team Leader / Project Manager

**QCoders** http://gcoders.com/



During work in this company I had only one general project which was divided to few small subprojects. InTouch http://intouch.inweb24.us/ InTouch is a email marketing system. Like MailChimp or Mandrill but with an emphasis in network marketing. I'm started this project from scratch. Gradually our team has grown up to 7 developers. It was first experience with Node.js on commercial project.

#### Primary Responsibilities:

Project management

Team management (team of seven members)

Estimating and resource planning

Design and development of system architecture

Design and development of source code

Database design and development

GUI design

Code review

#### Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: Node.js

Frameworks: Express, Backbone, Bootstrap

Databases: MongoDB Documentation: RAML

QA: Mocha

Another tools: Less, Jade, Grunt, Bower, NPM

#### 2011 - 2012, Senior Software Developer / Team Leader

Quadecco http://quadecco.de/



Development of many projects for outsourcing company using following technologies

#### Primary Responsibilities:

Team management

Estimating and resource planning

Design and development of system architecture

Design and development of source code

Database design and development

GUI design

Code review

#### Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: YII, Zend Framework, jQuery, Mootools

Databases: MySQL, MSSQL

## 2009 - 2011, Senior Software Developer / Team Leader

**ZFort Group** http://www.zfort.com.ua/



Development of many projects for outsourcing company using following technologies

#### Primary Responsibilities:

Team management

Estimating and resource planning

Design and development of system architecture

Design and development of source code

Database design and development

GUI design

Code review

#### Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: YII, PRADO, Zend Framework, jQuery

Databases: MySQL

## 2007 - 2009, Software Developer

**Intetics Co** http://intetics.com/



Development of many projects for outsourcing company using following technologies

## Primary Responsibilities:

Code development

Database development

## Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: jQuery Databases: MySQL

## 2005 - 2006, Junior Software Developer

**Letwork** http://www.letwork.com/



Development of many projects for outsourcing company using following technologies

Primary Responsibilities:

Code development

Database development

Used technologies and tools:

Platforms: PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS

Databases: MySQL